singaporepools.com 2019-12-25

# Singapore Pools Personal Data Protection and Privacy Policy

Singapore Pools Personal Data Protection and Privacy Policy
Singapore Pools places great importance on the confidentiality, privacy and
protection of personal data. This policy sets out the way we handle personal
data provided to us.
1.    What We Collect
1.1   We collect and use personal data necessary to conduct our business with
      you. The types of data we collect may include, but is not limited to:
      a. Full name
      b. Identity document number e.g. NRIC, FIN, passport number
      c. Photographs or video images from which an individual can be clearly
          identified
      d. Mobile or residential telephone number
      e. Personal E-mail address
      f. Residential address
      g. Nationality
      h. Date of Birth
1.2   Close-circuit television (CCTV) footage recording movement, where the
      individuals may be identified, are primarily for security purpose,
      investigations into customer complaints and other authorised purpose.
      Singapore Pools does not use CCTV footage for marketing purpose.
2.    When We Collect
2.1   When you open a Singapore Pools Account or when you update your
      personal particulars.
2.2    When you attend our corporate events or respond to our programmes,
      contests or survey.
2.3    When your image is captured by our photographers or videographers at
      our events.
2.4   When your image is captured on our CCTV system.
2.5   When you apply for a job with us.
                                   Page 1 of 7

2.6  When you provide feedback or contact customer service officers.
2.7  When you claim prize amounts above $5,000 at our Main Branch (210
     Middle Road) with a winning ticket.
3.   Purposes for Collection, Use and Disclosure of Your
     Personal Data
3.1  Singapore Pools collects data only for the specified purpose(s). Where
     the data is used for communicating product-related information, we
     operate on opt-in basis, and within the scope of consent.
3.2  To send you information, promotions, updates and marketing and
     advertising material. We do not make cold calls or use any third-party
     contact lists for communicating product-related information.
3.3  To respond to your requests and queries.
3.4  To enforce our rules and regulations, contractual and legal rights and
     obligations.
3.5  To ensure security for our premises.
3.6  To facilitate the employment of staff by Singapore Pools.
3.7  To comply with the law, any requests from law enforcement and
     regulatory officials, or orders of court.
3.8  To process payment transactions.
3.9  Towards any other purpose of use for which we have obtained your
     consent, express or implied.
3.10 We may disclose your personal data to third party service providers,
     agents and other organisations we have engaged to perform any of the
     aforementioned purposes for us.
                                    Page 2 of 7

4.  Protection of Your Personal Data
4.1 All data is handled in accordance with Singapore Pools’ Security Policy,
    which covers measures to prevent the unauthorized disclosure or loss of
    personal data.
4.2 All Singapore Pools staff are trained in the proper handling and
    protection of personal data.
4.3 All Singapore Pools vendors and suppliers are obligated to abide by our
    data privacy and protection policies.
4.4 Singapore Pools will not reveal details of your personal data to any other
    person unless we have your permission or is required under a legal
    obligation or any other duty to do so.
4.5 Access to your personal data is on a need-to-know basis.
5.  Accuracy of Your Personal Data
5.1 Singapore Pools will correct any inaccurate data when notified by the
    authorised party.
6.  Retention of Your Personal Data
6.1 Singapore Pools will retain such personal data in accordance with
    respective business needs and/or legal requirements.
6.2 Singapore Pools will securely dispose of or anonymise personal data
    which it can reasonably determine is no longer needed.
                                  Page 3 of 7

7.   Withdrawal of Your Consent
7.1  You can withdraw your consent previously given in regard to the
     processing of your personal data, through the “unsubscribe” or opt-out
     clause attached to our marketing communications. If you wish to make a
     blanket withdrawal of consent, you can do so by filling up a Blanket
     Withdrawal of Consent Form (refer to Annex A).
7.2  Upon receiving any withdrawal of consent, we shall acknowledge the
     withdrawal request and confirm that the marketing communication will
     stop within 5 working days.
8.   Access and Correction of Your Personal Data
8.1 You can obtain access and make corrections to your personal data records,
    via the following:
     a) Customer Service Line: 6786 6688
     b) Written mail: Singapore Pools (Private) Limited, 210 Middle Road,
         #01-01 Singapore 188994
     c) Online feedback form on Singapore Pools’ website
         (http://www.singaporepools.com.sg/en/cu/Pages/default.aspx)
8.2  We will make the necessary amendments and confirm that these have
     been made as soon as practicable upon our receipt of your request.
8.3  If you have any questions or feedback relating to your personal data or
     our Personal Data Protection and Privacy Policy, you can contact us via
     customer service line, written mail or online feedback form.
9.   Transfer of Your Personal Data Out of Singapore
9.1  Singapore Pools may transfer, store and/ or process your personal data by
     a party outside of Singapore.
9.2  We will ensure that the party receiving, storing and/ or processing your
     personal data outside of Singapore protects your personal data at a
     standard at least comparable to the protection under the Personal Data
     Protection Act (“PDPA”).
                                   Page 4 of 7

9.3  We will ensure that the party coming into contact with your personal data
     outside Singapore:
     a) Complies with the PDPA, all applicable laws and regulations; and
     b) Takes appropriate measures to ensure such compliance by
         implementing the necessary data protection.
10. Collection, Use or Disclosure of Your NRIC Numbers (or
     Copies of NRIC) and Retention of Your Physical NRIC
10.1 Singapore Pools is generally not allowed to collect, use or disclose NRIC
     numbers (or copies of NRIC). We may do so only in the following
     specified circumstances:
     a) We may collect, use or disclose your NRIC number (or copy of NRIC)
         without your consent if it is required under the law; and
     b) Where we find it necessary to accurately establish or verify the
         identity of you to a high degree of fidelity, we may collect, use or
         disclose your NRIC number with notification and consent.
10.2 The treatment for NRIC numbers also applies to Birth Certificate
     numbers, Foreign Identification Numbers (“FIN”), Work Permit numbers
     and passport numbers.
10.3 Singapore Pools should generally not retain your physical NRIC unless
     the retention of the physical NRIC is required under the law. The
     treatment for retention of physical NRIC applies to other identification
     documents containing the NRIC numbers or other national identification
     numbers (e.g. driver’s licence, passport and work pass).
11. Complaints Handling Process
11.1 If you are aware of any actual or potential breach of security in relation to
     personal data, you can report the incident/complaint to Singapore Pools
     Customer Service via customer service line, written mail or online
     feedback form. Customer Service will forward the incident/complaint to
     Data Protection Officer (“DPO”). DPO will assess the incident/complaint
     and carry out investigations if necessary.
                                    Page 5 of 7

12. Update
12.1 Singapore Pools reserves the right to amend this Personal Data Protection
     and Privacy Policy at any time by posting such changes on our Corporate
     Websites.
                                                 (Updated as at 26 Nov 2019)
                                  Page 6 of 7

                                                                      Annex A
Blanket Withdrawal of Consent Form
Name : ___________________________________
Contact details
E-mail : ___________________________________
Mobile number : ___________________________
Postal address : ____________________________
                 ____________________________
       I hereby revoke all and any consent previously given to Singapore Pools
for product-related information. Singapore Pools may only contact me on
transaction or other business-related matters.
_________________                      ________________
Signature                              Date
                                    Page 7 of 7
